Guide to the Cedric J. Robinson and Elizabeth P. Robinson Collection on Third World News Review TAM.835
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Third World News Review Episodes, 1981-2015; 1.67 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and a cassette box; 1.79 Terabytes in 496 computer files; 3 U-matic; 15 VHS; 29 audiocassettes
  - March 9, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_457
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Bethnal Green trio and brides of ISIL; the death of Ivana Hoffmann by ISIL; the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees published report about Syrian refugee women; negotiations to end the war in South Sudan; military efforts to stop Boko Haram and Boko Haram's allegiance to ISIS; and the Iguala mass kidnapping in Mexico and protests against corrupt police forces.
  - March 23, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_458
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics included the Israeli elections and Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's opposition to a two state solution; the civil war in Yemen; political instability in Brazil with protests against President Dilma Rousseff and Petrobras; the trial of Karim Wade and prison sentencing; the death of Prime Minister Lee Kuan Yew; the Mamasapano clash; and the deportation of Shin Eun-mi from South Korea.
  - March 30, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_459
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Thomas Jacob and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include political instability in India and the dominant Bharatiya Janata Party (BJP); racial tensions in India; food safety concerns in Lebanon; the U.S. and other allies removing themselves from the civil war in Yemen; and the Nigerian general elections.
  - April 2, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_460
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Katia McClain. Discussed topics included Bulgaria tightening its border with Turkey and building a wall to keep refugees from the Middle East and North Africa out; the change of the political landscape on Bulgaria over 25 years; the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank; the arrest of Palestinian activist Khalida Jarrar by Israel; Mumia Abu-Jamal; and the deaths of Günter Grass and Eduardo Galeano.
  - June 15, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_461
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Israel preempting a UN report by defending the Gaza conflict; Aung San Suu Kyi's visit to China; China publishing white papers about its future planning and reforms; the anniversary of the Bandung Conference; Nigeria, Chad, Niger, Cameroon, and Sudan to form a regional force against Boko Haram; and the trial of President Omar al-Bashir by the International Criminal Court.
  - June 22, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_462
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Jovian Radheshwar (South Asia) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the UN Gaza Inquiry's discovery of credible allegations of war crimes committed in 2014 by both Israel and Palestine; the arrests of Khalida Jarrar and Khader Adnan; Prime Minister Narendra Modi leading a mass yoga session in New Delhi and the Bharatiya Janata Party's use of yoga as a political weapon; the Cuban Five's visit to South Africa; South Africa being ordered to surrender President Omar al-Bashir after his indictment by the International Criminal Court.
  - July 6, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_463
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the Greek debt crisis and Greek bailout referendum; economic problems in Argentina; Cuba becoming the first country to eliminate mother-to-child transmissions of HIV and syphilis; Argentina's development of a genetic data bank due to large number of missing people; and controversies surrounding General César Milani of Argentina.
  - July 13, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_464
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gary Colmenar and Gerard Pigeon. Discussed topics include a Burundian crisis due to the presidential election results; the end of the South Sudanese Civil War; immigration from Africa into Europe; the Bardo National Museum attack and Sousse attacks in Tunisia; President François Hollande's tour of Sub-Saharan Africa; Puerto Rico's debt crisis; the Dominican Republic deporting Haitians; President Barack Obama given authority to expedite negotiations for a massive trade deal with countries on the Pacific Rim; and the anniversary of the Russell–Einstein Manifesto.
  - July 20, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_465
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Jovian Radheshwar (South Asia). Discussed topics include the re-establishment of diplomatic relations with Cuba, the history of Cuba, and the Cuban Revolution; the signing of Iran's nuclear deal; the rise in farmer suicides in India due to debts; the fight over land bill in the Indian Parliament; and the Statue of Unity in India.
  - July 27, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_466
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Gerard Pigeon and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include Turkish involvement in the Syrian Civil War; the U.S. and Turkey striking an agreement relating to the fight against ISIS; runner Dutee Chand winning her case on behalf of high testosterone female athletes; controversy surrounding the Burundian presidential election; and the trial of President Hissène Habré.
  - August 10, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_467
    The moderator of the episode was Elizabeth Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Katia McClain. Discussed topics include Ukrainian officials creating a blacklist of "anti-Ukrainian" people and subjects; Ukrainian decommunization laws and the deteriorating infrastructure of Ukraine; rapidly growing cases of HIV/AIDS in Ukraine; government debt crisis in Puerto Rico and growing poverty; the upcoming elections in Argentina; and ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestine.
  - September 28, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_468
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Hector Javkin and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the coup in Burkina Faso; Egyptian students returning to university after warnings against anti-government protest; political murals on Mohamed Mahmoud street in Egypt; the Yemeni Civil War; Pope Francis' visit to Cuba; demonstrations about Iguala mass kidnappings in Mexico; and demonstrations in Argentina for the "Night of the Pencils"
  - October 9, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_469
    The moderator of the episode was Cedric Robinson and the guests were Maryam Griffin (Palestine) and Elizabeth Robinson. Discussed topics include the increase in the number of Syrian refugees heading to Europe; ISIS; the attempted global crackdown on refugees; the release of paralympian Oscar Pistorius from prison; the gold miner silicosis litigation case in South Africa; and the ongoing violence in the Israeli–Palestinian conflict.
  - October 26, 2015, TW_TAM_835_ER_470
    The moderator was Cedric Robinson and the guests included Elizabeth Robinson, Ralph Ambruster-Sandoval, Lucy Edwards, Hector Javkin, Ilya Ahmadizadeh, Gary Colmenar, Katia McClain, Jim Phillips, and Gerard Pigeon. This was the final episode of Third World News Review and it was a retrospective episode consisting of farewell messages from guests, guests reminiscing about their time of the show, why they joined the show, and the history of the show.
  - Undated Episodes
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0012)
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0021)
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0022)
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0028)
    - Audio (Box 4, Audiocassette 835_0029)
    - Video (Box 5, Vhs 835_0035)
    - Video (Box 6, Vhs 835_0045)
    - Video (Box 6, Vhs 835_0046)
    - Video (Box 6, Vhs 835_0048)
    - Video (Box 6, U-matic 835_0043)
    - Video (Box 6, U-matic 835_0044)